JESSE KRIM

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER ☑ jesse.krim@gmail.com

- jessekrim.com
- **4** 201-704-5513
- **?** Franklin Lakes, NJ
- f jesse.krim
- in jessekrim
- jakrim

Summary

I am a full stack javascript developer passionate about working in startups and studying the world's most successful individuals in the technology industry. My goal is to work within a team of experienced and driven engineers building a product capable of scaling to millions of users. My passion for startups led me to San Francisco where I worked on the business side of an application finishing a Series A fundraise, and later to Las Vegas where I polished my sales and operational skills in a SaaS technology company. I have spent the last 10 months diving into software development to expand my capabilities and future value within technology companies. Please visit jessekrim.com for more.

Education

Syracuse University 2017 BS Information Management and Technology Minor: Entrepreneurship Study Abroad: Tel Aviv University, Israel (Entrepreneurship Program) Spring 2016

Hack Reactor 2019
512 hours over 2.5 months
learning JavaScript
methodologies, frameworks
and libraries for full stack
software development

Skills

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES:

JavaScript, Node, React, Redux, Webpack, SQL, MongoDB, Git + Github, REST, GraphQL, MVC, TDD, JIRA BUSINESS: Sales, Marketing, Project Management, Operations, Customer Service, Business Development HOBBIES & PASSIONS:

Business, Innovation,

Technology, Cars, Golf, Self-Development, Skiing, Scuba Diving, Hebrew, Music & Drumset, Sustainability

Employment

Ribbon Labs Inc

Operations + Community Management

San Francisco, CA June 2016 - Current

- Communicate with the CEO to QA 80+ application builds and log 1000+ bugs into JIRA.
- Prepare app for beta and public launch, contribute in various iOS store launch processes.
- Manage documentation of all business operations, from Investor docs to future app sprints and data.
- · Contribute to marketing, investor, and partner decks, as well as design notes for designers and developers.
- · Advance relationships with current and future investors by on-boarding them onto the application.

Dan Lier Sales Mastery

Las Vegas

National Sales Trainer

July 2018 - Jan. 2019

- Built and automated sales organization, executed strategy that generated \$28,000+ in revenue in 2 months.
- Executed sales presentations to sell 158 tickets and advance Dan Lier's live events business.
- Cultivated relationships with customers in the auto and insurance industry and uncovered new customer needs.

LightSpeed VT

Las Vegas

Client and Operations Management + Sales

May 2018 - Nov. 2018

- Worked with dev-team to oversee implementation of new features in the backend and frontend of software.
- Created marketing plan and long-term company growth strategy.
- Designed and implemented new culture for employees within the organization.
- · Constructed operational processes and trainings for the new sales team.

Zaitoun Ventures

Tel Aviv, Israel

Project Management Intern

Feb. 2016 - June 2016

- Redesigned, edited, and created new content for the company website.
- Managed a marketing campaign for a tech startup and investment.
- Managed an Israeli-Chinese Entrepreneurial Innovation Fellowship program around Israel.

Software Projects & More

Advanced React Techniques

2019

A todo list using local state, and advanced react hooks such as useReducer, useContext, useEffect, useRef.

React-Redux (front-end) App

2019

A mock Youtube project using the Youtube API. State is kept in the Redux store utilizing redux actions and reducers to keep state in the application.

Favorite Movies (full stack) App

2019

Fetched data from an API, server-side rendered on an Express server to a React.js front end, and created persistent data storage for a "favorite movies" component with Mongodb and SQL.

MySQL MVC App

2019

A project utilizing the MVC methodology with MySQL.

Influis

June 2018 - Current

Influis is a professional audio social network that is the most efficient way to discover, share, and produce messages. (Recently lost the domain and the website... new domain will be influis.io).

One Minute Mindset

Oct. 2017 - Curre

@OneMinuteMindset on Instagram displays my passion for studying the world's most successful, influential, and knowledgeable people.

The evolution of user navigation. Is Facebook winning the internet?

Oct. 2016

Studied the major players in the internet space and how navigation is facilitated in an Information Architecture. I talk about how Facebook is taking over the internet.

Global Sandbox Consultant

Sept. 2016 - May 2017

Selected to consult for three teams of students from Syracuse University, Tsinghua (China), Ahmedabad (India), Kiev Poly (Ukraine), and JKUAT (Kenya). Groups created a micro-multinational venture leveraging their countries resources and appealing to the 18-29 demographic.

Awards

Syracuse iSchool · Spring Break in Silicon Valley + Entretech NYC

2017

Chosen to join two five-day student trips to Silicon Valley and New York City visiting 24 technology companies each trip, meeting CEOs, alumni, and learning about their culture, funding, operations, and more. I created a short video with my top 15 takeaways from SBinSV: http://bit.ly/2rDJo3r

PMI · CAPM - Project Management Certification

Dec. 2016

Enrolled in an 8 week project management certification course to receive a CAPM certification.

Syracuse University · Fast Forward Syracuse

Mar. 2015

Won \$1000 from a competition to benefit student life and built a prototype of an all-weather bench cover placed on campus